本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
《反恐24小时》前情提要
Previously on 24
诺尔斯先生  我是杰克·鲍尔
Mr. Knowles, my name is Jack Bauer.
乔纳斯·霍奇斯手上持有军用级生化武器
Jonas Hodges is in possession of a military-grade bioweapon.
我试图拦截毒气罐时被感染了
I was contaminated when trying to intercept the canisters.
先生  我保证  武器就在你们的基地
I promise you, sir, the weapon is on your base.
你是否知道武器可能所在的位置
Do you have any idea where they might be?
我想我可能知道
I think I might.
我是奉美国总统之令行事
I have an order from the President of the United States.
奉命来搜查这栋楼
To search this building.
有大规模杀伤性武器吗
Are there weapons of mass destruction?
有任何武器吗
Are there weapons of any kind?
给你5分钟时间
You've got five minutes
你和你的手下坐着这些直升机
To get these helicopters flying out of here
给我离开这儿
With all of you on board.
拉里  我要你和你的人
Larry, I want you and your men
佯装按霍奇斯的意思准时撤兵
To pull out on Hodges' Timetable.
托尼  你想办法潜伏下来
Tony, you're gonna need to find a way to stay behind.
我们会通过无线电让你
We're gonna get your vectors over to a man
跟一个斯塔克伍德内部人士取得联系
That we contacted inside Starkwood.
他叫道格拉斯·诺尔斯
His name is Douglas Knowles.
他觉得自己知道武器藏在哪里
He believes he knows where the weapons are.
待在这  我马上回来
Stay here. I'll be right back.
杰克
Jack!
叫医护人员来
We need a medic!
生化剂比我们想的要厉害得多
The bioagent is more virulent than we thought.
我们所做的只是掩蔽症状而已
All we're doing here is just masking the symptoms.
我明白
I understand.
不过有件事你也许会考虑一下
There's something you may want to consider.
什么事
What's that?
一种采用干细胞的可能疗法
A possible treatment using stem cells
需从基因匹配的捐赠者身上提取
From a genetically compatible donor.
我看过你的档案  你有个女儿
I saw your file, and it says you have a daughter.
我不想把我的女儿牵扯进来
I don't want my daughter involved in this.
这应该由她来决定
It should be her choice.
不是
Well, it's not.
我才是快死的那个
I'm the one who's dying.
我进来了
I'm in.
但他们带走了诺尔斯
But they got Knowles.
你的那一点点忠心
A little loyalty.
我还是应得的吧
Wasn't that the least I deserved?
你不能和政府作对啊
You can't take on the federal government.
我看见武器了
I have a visual on the weapon.
是毒气罐
Okay, those are the canisters.
我去通知史密斯上将  目标已找到并确认
I'll notify Admiral Smith the target is located and confirmed.
您还记得斯塔克伍德驻扎在巴基斯坦吧
You remember Starkwood was deployed to Pakistan,
那时我们征用过一种导弹系统
That we requisitioned a missile system at that Time.
三枚那样的导弹
Well, three of those missiles
现正装满病原体
Are now loaded with a pathogen
目标是东部沿海各城市
And aimed at cities on our eastern seaboard.
您要对此次会晤守口如瓶
You will keep this conversation to yourself
并且召回战斗机
And turn the planes around.
您要是不答应的话  总统阁下
And if you do not comply, Madam President,
我就别无选择
I will have no choice
只能发射那些导弹
But to launch those missiles.
史密斯上将  取消空袭
Abort the air strike, Admiral Smith.
阁下  恕我直言
Ma'am, with all respect...
见鬼  上将
Damn it, admiral.
马上取消空袭
Abort the air strike immediately!
以下情节发生在凌晨1点至2点间
The following takes place between 1 a.m. and 2 a.m.
翻译：吉吉    祭司    aiai    非燕   校对：何何   非燕
■
时间轴：after    后期：冰河   总监：何何
托尼  我是杰克  听到没
Tony, it's Jack. Do you copy?
杰克  究竟发生什么事了
Jack, what the hell is going on?
F-18战斗机呢
Where are those F-18s?
蒂姆·伍兹刚从白宫打电话来说
Tim Woods just called from the White House.
总统取消了空袭
The president canceled the air strike.
什么
What?
为什么
Why?
她觉得我们的情报
She doesn't believe our intel
不足以构成军事打击的理由
Is strong enough to justify military action.
她疯了吗
Is she out of her mind?
杰克  我亲眼见到那些毒气罐
Jack, I saw those canisters with my own eyes.
你也看见了  它们就在那地堡里
So did you. they're in that bunker.
-没有比这更好的证据了  -我知道
- She's not gonna get any better intel than that. - I know.
是想不明白  但现在
It doesn't make any sense, but right now,
总统下令  你和周边的小队
We've got a presidential order to pull you out
得马上撤出斯塔克伍德
Of the Starkwood compound, along with the perimeter teams.
托尼  拉里已经知道了总统的决定
Tony, Larry's been told the president's decision.
他正准备把队伍撤走
He's preparing to move his teams out
但这之前他得先把你弄出去
but he's got to get you out of there first.
他会给你发送坐标  在西南边上
He'll be sending you coordinates for an exfiltration point
有一个逃出的缺口
Along the southwest perimeter.
托尼
Tony?
等等
Hold on a second.
托尼  怎么了
Tony, what's going on?
杰克  我可能知道为什么总统取消空袭了
Jack, I might know why the president called off that air strike.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我觉得斯塔克伍德拥有地对地导弹
I think Starkwood's got surface-to-surface missiles.
这些导弹正可用来部署生化武器
That's how they're gonna deploy the bioweapon.
你怎么知道的
How do you know this?
有辆油罐车刚停在了地堡旁边
A fuel truck just pulled up next to the bunker
武器就在地堡里
Where they're storing the weapons.
他们正把RP-7输送进地下燃料库里
They're pumping RP-7 into an underground depot.
RP-7是什么
What's RP-7?
是一种助推燃料  只用于地对地导弹
It's a propellant only used in surface-to-surface missiles.
托尼  你确定吗
Tony, are you sure?
杰克  这东西就在我眼前呢
I'm looking right at it, Jack.
你带了C-4炸药没
Do you have any C-4 on you?
带了三个  还有一个遥控引爆器
Yeah, I've got three charges and a remote detonator.
你觉得你可以进到地下燃料库吗
Do you think you can gain access to the underground fuel depot?
我觉得可以赌一把
Yeah, I think we've got a play,
但我得赶在油罐车开走前
But I've got to move soon...
赶快行动了
Before that fuel truck pulls away.
好  原地待命
Okay, I want you to maintain your position.
我去给总统打电话
I'm gonna call the president.
跟我来
Come with me.
蒂姆  什么事
What is it, Tim?
总统阁下  参谋长联席会议委员们
Madam President, the Joint Chiefs
开始质疑您
Are beginning to question your decision
取消对斯塔克伍德进行空中打击的决定了
To call off the air strike against Starkwood.
他们认为  从托尼·阿尔梅达那里
They think the intelligence we received from Tony Almeida
收到的情报很充分  我们可能正错失
Was sufficient and that we may be missing
毁灭生化武器的大好时机
An opportunity to destroy the bioweapons.
蒂姆  我已经下了命令
I gave my orders, Tim.
不进行空中打击
No air strike.
也不进行针对斯塔克伍德的一切军事行动
No military action of any kind against Starkwood.
现在  我要你去处理好联席参谋长会议事宜
Now, I asked you to handle the Joint Chiefs;
并安抚好他们
Handle them.
阁下  我会尽力而为  但斗胆问一下
I'll do my best, ma'am, But if I may...
我们下一步计划是什么
What is our next move?
乔纳斯·霍奇斯在来白宫的路上了
Jonas Hodges is coming to the White House.
他想跟我单独谈谈
He wants to speak with me alone.
-他来干什么  -我不知道
- For what possible reason? - I don't know.
总统阁下  您的顾问们
Madam President, shouldn't your advisors
不应该出席这次会面吗
Be at that meeting?
蒂姆  别再向我发难了
Tim, stop asking me questions.
如果你真想帮忙
If you want to help,
乔纳斯·霍奇斯要来的消息
Make sure as few people as possible know
让越少人知道越好
That Jonas Hodges is coming here.
把他从东南面的便门带进来
And bring him in through the southeast service entrance.
什么事
Yes?
总统阁下  杰克·鲍尔
Madam President, Jack Bauer
和蕾妮·沃克从联邦调查局打来电话
And Renee Walker are calling from FBI.
你通知过调查局了吧
You did speak to FBI?
是的  阁下  五分钟前
Yes, ma'am, five minutes ago.
我跟他们说了您取消空袭的原因
I gave them your reason for calling off
但不得不提醒您
The air strike, but I must warn you,
他们对此也深表怀疑
They were skeptical as well.
准备好接霍奇斯
Be ready for Hodges.
鲍尔先生
Mr. Bauer,
沃克探员  我是总统
Agent Walker, this is the president.
总统阁下  我得跟您谈谈
Madam President, we need to talk.
不  鲍尔先生  不需要
No, Mr. Bauer, we don't.
你得听我说
You need to listen.
感谢你为了收集这些情报所做的一切
I appreciate everything that you have done in gathering this intel,
但在下令进行空袭前
But I still need more
我还需要更多信息
Before I can authorize an air strike.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
总统阁下  恕我直言
Madam President, with all due respect,
我觉得您没跟我们说实话
I don't believe you're being truthful with us.
什么
Excuse me?
我认为您取消空袭
I think you called off the air strike
是因为乔纳斯·霍奇斯拥有
Because Jonas Hodges is in possession
载有生化武器的地对地导弹
Of surface-to-surface missiles armed with the bioweapon,
他以此要挟
And he's threatening to use them
防止您对他采取行动
In case you try to take action against him.
总统阁下  托尼·阿尔梅达亲眼见到
Madam President, Tony Almeida witnessed a truck
油罐车把RP-7火箭助推剂输送到
Pumping RP-7 rocket fuel into an underground depot
地堡旁的燃料库里
Situated right next to the bunker
生化武器就藏在地堡中
Where the bioweapons are being stored.
而RP-7火箭助推剂的唯一用途
The only purpose for RP-7 rocket fuel
就是发射导弹
Is to launch missiles.
总统阁下  请告诉我们实情好吗
Madam President, please just tell us the truth.
杰克  霍奇斯持有13枚
Jack, Hodges has 13 Python missiles
载有生化武器的巨蟒导弹
Armed with the bioweapons.
其中三枚正对准美国城市
Three are currently aimed at American cities.
他要求我召回战斗机  否则就会发射导弹
He demanded that I recall the planes, or he would launch.
霍奇斯葫芦里卖的什么药啊
What does Hodges want?
我不知道  但他要求几分钟后在白宫
I don't know... But he's requested a face-to-face meeting.
跟我面对面谈话
He'll be at the White House in a few minutes.
总统阁下  他想面对面对话的唯一目的
Madam President, the only reason he wants a face-to-face meeting
就是摆出他的要求
is to lay out his demands,
不管他要求什么  您都不能妥协
And whatever they are, you cannot negotiate with him.
杰克  我并未打算跟他谈判
I'm not planning on negotiating with him, Jack.
一旦他摊牌了
Once he places his cards on the table,
我确信我能  我能让他认识到
I am sure that I can... I can make him realize
他所做的这一切只是枉费心机
The futility of what he is trying to do.
乔纳斯·霍奇斯是叛国者  是恐怖分子
Jonas Hodges is a traitor and a terrorist,
基于他今天的所作所为
And after everything that's happened today,
你还真的天真到认为能说服他
Are you really naive enough to believe that you can simply talk to him
改变他的想法
And change his mind?
杰克  这方面我有经验的
I'm not new at this, Jack,
而且现在  我已别无选择了
And right now, I don't have another option.
总统阁下  您仍有选择的
Madam President, you do.
托尼·阿尔梅达还在斯塔克伍德里面
Tony Almeida is still inside Starkwood.
我下过令让他马上撤离的
I ordered him exfiltrated immediately.
他还在那里干什么
What's he still doing there?
在我跟您商量过之前  我叫他原地待命
I asked him to stand by until I could talk to you.
他认为自己能够进到燃料库
He believes he can gain access to the fuel depot
放置连环炸药装置
And lay a series of explosive charges
从而摧毁那些导弹
And take the missiles out.
我相信能成功  但我们得赶快行动
Now, I believe this can work, but we need to act quickly.
毒气不会扩散吗
What about the bioweapons?
RP-7火箭助推剂燃烧起来有5000度
RP-7 rocket fuel burns at 5,000 degrees.
毒气会被燃烧殆尽
There will be nothing left.
一旦摧毁了武器  拉里·莫斯跟他的队伍
Once the weapons are destroyed, Larry Moss and his teams
就能进入斯塔克伍德并封锁那里
Can move in on Starkwood and lock it down.
霍奇斯给他的手下下令
Hodges gave standing orders to his men
一旦发现政府介入
To launch the missiles at the first detection
立即发射导弹
Of government interference.
杰克  如果阿尔梅达被发现了
If Almeida is detected,
会有成千上万美国人丧生
Thousands of Americans will die, Jack.
总统阁下  我知道这有风险
Madam President, I know that there's a risk,
但要是没有成功的把握
But I would not be asking you to do this
我也不会求您这么做
If I didn't think it would work.
拜托了  我求您了
Please, I am begging you.
相信我
Trust me.
医生有没有说你还能活多久
How long didthe doctors give you to live?
他们还不确定
Uh, they're not sure,
但是已经开始发病了
But the pathogen has started to take effect.
那我也没什么可威胁你的了  对吗
Then there's not much I can threaten you with, is there?
觉得对的  你就去做吧
I expect you'll do what you think is right.
那是什么意思
What the hell does that mean?
她希望我们继续干
She wants us to go in.
但她没有授权啊
But she didn't authorize it.
她不能
She can't.
这只能是一次秘密行动
She needs this to be a covert operation.
若有半点差池
If something were to go wrong
致使导弹发射出去
And those missiles were to be launched,
总统必须得发誓
The president needs to be able to swear
这绝对只是我们单方面擅自行动
Under oath that we were working on our own
她希望我们继续行动
She wants us to go in.
通知拉里  我们得快点
Notify Larry. we need to move fast.
我告诉过你我能把你带到白宫
I told you I'd get you to the White House.
只是没想到  是以这种方式
I just didn't think it would be under these conditions.
太有才了
It was brilliant, you know.
长官  您指什么
What was that, sir?
就是你让阿尔梅达相信
What you didto make Almeida think
你会背叛我
That you were betraying me.
太有才了
Quite brilliant.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
格雷格  你不顾个人安危
You put yourself in harm's way, Greg,
我会铭记在心
And I'll never forget that.
不敢相信  我居然紧张了
I can't believe... I'm feeling nervous.
长官  你会没事的
You're gonna do fine, sir.
谢谢你  蒂姆
Thank you, Tim.
不客气
You're welcome.
感觉像是总统并没有批准此事
So, it sounds to me like the president didn't actually authorize this.
严格地说  她是没有
Technically, no.
更像是个间接命令
It was more of an... an indirect order,
但是拉里  她希望我们这么做
But believe me, Larry, she wants this to happen.
她要和霍奇斯会面
She's gonna meet with Hodges,
我们要把燃料罐炸掉
And we're gonna blow those fuel tanks.
拉里  你对这次行动有意见吗
Larry, do you have a problem with this?
事实上  没有
As a matter of fact, no.
没有任何意见
None whatsoever.
这些斯塔克伍德的杂种们竟敢招惹我的人
These Starkwood bastards drew on my men.
我盼着再进去跟他们干一场呢
I'm looking forward to getting back in there.
好的  让你的队伍原地待命
All right, have your teams hold their position
随时准备行动
And be ready to move.
相信我  爆炸时你会知道的
Believe me, you'll know when it happens.
好的
All right.
-托尼  我是杰克  听到没  -我在
- Tony, It's Jack. do you copy?  - Yeah, I'm here.
你说对了  那是导弹
You were right about the missiles.
总统证实了
The president confirmed it.
我们这次行动  必须秘密进行
We're gonna have to carry this out as a covert operation.
一旦导弹被销毁
Larry and his men are standing by to lock down Starkwood
拉里和他的部队就会封锁斯塔克伍德
As soon as the missiles have been destroyed.
-好  -托尼
- Good.  - Tony...
我要你干得神不知  鬼不觉
I need to know that you can do this without being detected.
霍奇斯已经下令
Hodges's given his men standing orders
出现任何形式违反协议的行为
To launch those missiles
立即发射导弹
if there's a breach of any kind.
我能做到
Yeah. I can do it.
祝你好运
Okay. Good luck.
好
Yeah.
这里完事了
We're done here.
我到周围巡逻下
I'm going to go run a perimeter check.
你不是才巡逻过吗
You said you just finished one.
我知道
I know.
但现在要加倍小心
But I don't think we can be too careful right now.
-喂  -是我
- yeah.  - It's me.
辅助罐已加满燃料做好准备了
Auxiliary tanks are fueled and ready.
已确认
Confirmed.
我稍后就下来
I'll be down in a few minutes.
收到
Copy that.
不许动
Freeze!
举起手来
Let me see your hands.
阿尔梅达
Almeida.
把枪放在地上
Put your gun on the ground.
慢慢地
Slowly.
踢出去
Kick it.
把他拖到卡车下面
Drag him under the truck.
快点  去啊
Now! let's go!
举起手来
Hands up.
你知道自己在做什么吗
What do you think you're doing?
带我去燃料罐那里
You're going to take me down to the fuel tanks.
走吧
Let's go.
打开
Open it up.
进去
Go ahead.
总统现在可以接见你们了
President will see you now.
很好  谢谢
Very good. Thank you.
霍奇斯先生
Mr. Hodges.
总统阁下
Madam President.
这位是格雷格·西顿
This is Greg Seaton,
我的助手
My associate.
他非同寻常
He's a remarkable man.
看起来不像
Doesn't look remarkable,
但是相信我  他是个天才
But believe me, he's a genius.
是啊  我认识西顿先生
Yes, I know Mr. Seaton.
没事了  先生们
Thank you, gentlemen.
还是老样子  对吧
It never gets old, does it?
走进总统办公室
Stepping into the... the Oval Office.
几乎
Almost
能闻到历史的味道
Smells of history.
我们能坐下来吗
Can we sit?
请坐
Please.
自从您上任以来
You know, this is the first Time
我还是第一次到这办公室来
I've been in this room since you were elected?
这我知道
I'm aware of that, yes.
在前任总统执政期间
Under your predecessor,
我每两个月会来一次
I used to drop by every couple of months.
我会向丹尼尔斯总统
I'd brief President Daniels
报告世界上都发生了些什么
On what was really going on in the world.
而现如今你却失了宠被晾在了一边
And you've been excluded now.
就是因为这个吗
Is that what this is about?
不  阁下
No, ma'am.
是关于让斯塔克伍德
It's about allowing Starkwood
完成它的既定使命
To fulfill the purpose for which was founded
保卫这个国家
Protecting this country.
你一直都在攻击这个国家
You have been attacking this country.
你和朱玛将军
You and General Juma
杀害了数以百计的无辜民众
Have killed hundreds of innocent people,
包括我的儿子
Including my son.
总统阁下
Madam President,
对于您儿子的死  我深表遗憾
I'm deeply sorry for your loss,
同时我也为今天逝去的那些生命而心碎
And my heart breaks for all the lives that were taken today,
但您认为我和此事有关
But I'm shocked that you would think that I had anything
-让我很是震惊  -我们有证据
- To do with it.  - we have evidence
表明你和朱玛狼狈为奸
That you've been working with Juma.
您的情报部门辜负了您的期望
Your intelligence agencies have failed you.
如果我知道朱玛的阴谋诡计
If I had known what Juma was up to,
我会竭尽所能地去阻止他得逞
I would have done everything in my power to stop him.
不如我们把这些莫须有的控告放到一边
So let's push aside all these baseless accusations
说不定我们还可以精诚合作
And maybe we can do some business here.
我洗耳恭听
I'm listening.
总统阁下
Madam President,
我知道您是历史系毕业的
I know you're a student of history,
您肯定清楚地知道
And so you're well aware
我们国家是借助私人部队的协助
That our nation's independence was won
才取得了独立
With the aid of private armies,
没有他们就没有这个国家的今天
And we can't survive without them.
您看把生化武器带进国门是多么易如反掌
Look how easy it was to get bioweapons into this country.
我们的国防不堪一击
Our defenses are fragile.
濒临崩溃
They're on the verge of collapse.
但亡羊补牢为时不晚
But it's not too late to do something about it.
那你有何高见呢
So what are you suggesting?
简言之
In short,
我想要个政府职位
I want a seat at the table.
斯塔克伍德要参与
Starkwood needs to be involved in the shaping
国内外军事政策的制定
Of military policy, domestic and global.
这听起来更像  你是想要第一把交椅
It sounds more like you want a seat at the head of the table.
总统阁下  我不是来篡权夺位的
Madam President, I'm not here to supplant your authority.
我是来提议精诚合作的
What I'm proposing is a partnership.
请考虑
Think of Starkwood
把斯塔克伍德作为军队的第五分支
As the fifth branch of the military.
格雷格
Greg?
这里包含了协议的基本条款
This contains the protocols that will serve as the basis of our agreement.
我建议咱们一起来看看
I suggest that we review them together.
乔纳斯  我同意会面
Jonas, I agreed to this meeting
是因为我想听听你想说些什么
Because I wanted to hear what you had to say.
但你的提议简直是敲诈勒索
But what you're proposing is blackmail.
您那是竟往最坏处想了啊
Well, that's putting it in the worst possible light.
你威胁说要杀害数以千计的平民
You are threatening to kill thousands of people.
我并不以此为荣
I'm not proud of this chapter.
我也第一次这样承认
I'm the first to admit it.
过去的就让它过去吧
And it's Time to turn the page.
今天这个国家经历了太多的血雨腥风
This country has seen enough bloodshed today.
总统阁下  为谋天下百姓之福祉
For the sake of the American people, Madam President,
我恳请您与我同舟共济
I implore you to work with me,
往日恩怨一笔勾销
And let's move past this.
请看文件  总统阁下
Pick up the document, Madam President.
我们走
Let's go.
快点起来  不然我把你留这了
Come on. get up now, or I'll leave you down here.
你不希望那样的  相信我  起来啊
And you don't want that, believe me. get up!
走
Let's go!
来啊
Come on!
怎么了
What is it?
代码363
Code 363.
我们该发射了
We're supposed to launch.
你确定不是错误警报
Are you sure it's not a false alarm?
无法判断
No way to tell.
但我们有作战命令
We've got standing orders, though.
启动发射序列
Let's start the launch sequence.
太迟了
Too late.
发射序列完成
Launch sequence complete.
输入开火密码
Enter the firing codes.
长官  我们得确认此事
Sir, we need to confirm this.
那不是标准程序
That's not the correct protocol.
我们会杀死一万人啊
We're about to kill 10,000 people.
我们应该打电话确认一下
We should get someone on the phone.
输入密码
Enter the codes.
马上
Now!
不行  长官
No, sir.
炸了  我们的人得手了  该咱们上场了
That's it. that's us. let's go.
出发
We're a go!
他完成任务了
It's done.
托尼
Tony?
托尼  听到了吗
Tony, do you copy?
如此规模的爆炸可能短路了他的通讯设备
An explosion of that magnitude would have shorted out his com.
我们只能等拉里和他的人进去后再说了
We're gonna have to wait for Larry and his men to move in.
上面写你想成为
It says here that you want
国防部战略计划组的核心成员
Active status in the Pentagon's Strategic Planning Group.
是的
That's correct.
那你就可以进入6级保密资料了
That would give you access to level 6 classified material.
即使副总统也没那个权限
Not even the vice president has that clearance.
这点没得商量
These points are nonnegotiable.
我不是来这跟你讨价还价的
I'm not here to debate them.
我们看下一部分关于
Let's review the next section,
参议院对斯塔克伍德外勤的监督权
Which concerns senate oversight of Starkwood field operations.
抱歉打扰  总统阁下
I'm sorry to interrupt, Madam President
我得跟您说点事
But I need to speak with you.
等等可以吗
Can it wait?
总统阁下  必须现在
No, ma'am, it can't.
失陪一下
Will you excuse me for a moment?
当然
Of course.
通讯卫星刚刚探测到
Satcom has just detected
斯塔克伍德基地发生了剧烈的爆炸
A massive explosion on the Starkwood compound.
生化武器设备已经被销毁了
The bioweapons facility has been destroyed.
-确定吗  -是的  阁下
- Are you sure? - Yes, ma'am.
这么大规模的爆炸
Judging by the size of the explosion,
几乎可以摧毁任何东西
Nothing could have survived.
但我不清楚是谁做的  不是我们的人干的
But I don't know how this happened. This wasn't us.
让调查局把斯塔克伍德封锁起来
Call FBI and have them lock down Starkwood.
-他们已经行动了  -很好
- They're already moving in. - Good.
这事结束之后  我要跟杰克·鲍尔通话
And when this is over, I want to speak to Jack Bauer.
好的  阁下
Yes, ma'am.
我没把握是否已说动她
I'm not sure I'm reaching her.
我觉得您干得很棒  长官
I think you handled it perfectly, sir.
很快就能见分晓了
We'll see.
你们要干嘛
What the hell is this?
把这些材料作为证据
Put this document into evidence
把这两个人抓起来
And take these men into custody.
你想干什么  你疯了吗
What are you thinking? Have you lost your mind?
乔纳斯  你的导弹已经被我们摧毁了
Jonas, we've taken out your missiles.
你玩完了
It's over.
不可能
That's impossible.
这是事实
It's the truth.
你被捕了
And you're under arrest.
你是个恐怖分子和杀人犯
You are a terrorist and a murderer
我要尽我一切所能
And I'm gonna do everything in my power
让你为犯下的罪行付出惨痛的代价
to make sure that you pay dearly for your crimes.
我唯一的罪过就是想保护我的祖国
My only crime is that I'm trying to protect my country!
你觉得逮捕我这事就完了吗
You think this ends with me?
我只是这次行动的冰山一角
I'm just a small cog in a very big machine.
稍等
Hold on.
你将面对的  是你无法想象的对手
You can't even begin to imagine what you're up against.
你在说些什么
What are you talking about?
你会知道的
You'll find out.
把他带出去
Get him out of here.
生化先遣小组的报告说
The advance biohazard team is reporting no trace
爆炸点附近没有监测到生化武器的痕迹
Of the bioweapon anywhere near the blast sight.
已在爆炸中全部被烧毁
It was incinerated in the explosion.
很好
Good.
-联系上托尼了吗  -还没
- Any word on Tony? - Not yet.
拉里正在基地里搜查
Larry's searching the compound now.
马上会有消息了
We should hear something soon.
鲍尔先生
Mr. Bauer,
总统的电话
You have a phone call; it's the president.
我在会议室接  谢谢
I'll take it in the conference room. thank you.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
总统阁下
Madam President.
鲍尔先生  乔纳斯·霍奇斯已经被捕
Mr. Bauer, Jonas Hodges is under arrest.
好消息
That's good news.
实在是太好了
That's very good.
杰克  你和你的队伍给了我一条出路
Jack, you and your team provided me with an option.
我和美国人民
And for that, I am deeply grateful.
都对你感激不尽
And so are the American people.
总统阁下  应该是托尼
Madam President, it was Tony Almeida
冒着生命危险摧毁了导弹
Who risked his life to destroy those missiles.
您知道  他现在正因一些
And as you know, he's facing arrest
导致今天事件的罪名而被追捕
For things he didleading up to today,
希望您也许
And I was hoping that maybe
可以
You could...
鲍尔先生
Yes, Mr. Bauer?
杰克
Jack?
抱歉  我
Um, I'm sorry, I...
忘记自己刚在说什么了
Completely forgot what I was saying.
你刚才在说阿尔梅达的事
You were talking about Mr. Almeida.
我的回答是  可以
And my answer is yes,
我会考虑到他今天所做的贡献
I-I will take his actions into account.
谢谢您
Thank you.
你怎么了
What's happening?
我  我不太确定
I-I-I'm not exactly sure.
杰克  我为你的遭遇而感到难过
Jack, I am so sorry you're going through this.
我真希望能为你做些什么
I wish that there were something I could do.
总统阁下  谢谢您的来电
M-Madam President, I appreciate this phone call.
但是我有事要挂机了
But I'm sorry. I-I have to go.
我了解
Of course.
谢谢您
Thank you.
乔纳斯·霍奇斯已经被捕
Jonas Hodges has been arrested.
你一和托尼联系上就通知我一声
Let me know as soon as you got Tony.
我要去梅瑟尔医生那一下
I need to go see Dr.Macer.
总统阁下  请讲
Yes, Madam President?
联系疾病预防控制中心的本·兰德利
Call Ben Landry at CDC.
跟他讲我要关于杰克·鲍尔
Tell him that I want real-Time updates
健康状况的即时消息
On Jack Bauer's condition.
是的  阁下
Yes, ma'am.
我们已把守住了所有入口和指挥所
We've secured all entry points and command posts
现在正对该基地进行地毯式搜查
And are sweeping the compound on a grid-by-gridbasis.
遇到反抗了吗
Are you meeting any resistance?
没
No.
他们都顺从地缴械投降了
They're surrendering peacefully and cooperating.
我觉得基地的大多数人
Most of the men on this base,
都不知道发生了什么事
I don't think they had any idea what was going on.
阿尔梅达呢
What about Almeida?
他在这
Uh, he's here.
找到他了
We found him.
-他还好吗  -只是些小伤和淤青
- Is he okay? - Some cuts and bruises,
其它的没事  他很好
But otherwise, he's in pretty good shape.
好的  很好
Good. good.
杰克知道的话  肯定会很高兴的
Jack will be glad to hear that.
蕾妮  听着
Listen, Renee...
我们认识也很久了
We've known each other a long Time, you know.
今天发生了太多的事
Um, so much stuff has happened today.
是啊
Yeah.
我们要好好谈谈了
We have a lot to talk about.
我知道
I know.
打扰一下  沃克探员
Excuse me, agent Walker.
您的客人到了  她等在会客区
Your visitor's arrived. She's in the waiting area.
好的  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
拉里  我要挂了
Larry, I've got to go.
-金·鲍尔来了  -杰克的女儿吗
- Kim Bauer's here. - Jack's daughter?
是啊  我叫她来的
Yes. I-I asked her to come.
治疗杰克的病有一种试验疗法
There's this experimental treatment
但是需要匹配的干细胞
For Jack's disease, but he needs compatible stem cells.
疗效不确定  但这是杰克唯一的希望
It's a long shot, but it's the only hope he's got.
很好
Okay.
及时通知我结果  好吧
Let me know how it goes, all right?
会的  我挂了
I will. I'm going off com.
好的
All right.
他们在说金·鲍尔吗
Didthey say something about Kim Bauer?
是啊  她现在在调查局
Yeah, she's at FBI
为了帮助杰克进行治疗
Helping with a treatment for Jack,
什么干细胞疗法
Some, uh, some kind of stem cell therapy.
他会好起来吗
So they think he's gonna be all right?
不容乐观
Didn't sound promising.
托尼  我也很为难
Listen, Tony, this isn't easy for me,
但是我接到命令  要求逮捕你
But, uh... I'm under orders to take you into federal custody.
我了解
Yeah, I know.
你刚才的英勇壮举
You dida brave thing here.
救了几千条性命
Probably saved thousands of lives.
说真的
For the record,
我觉得这不是你应得的回报
I don't think this is how you should be repaid.
感谢你能这么说  不过
I appreciate that, but, uh...
我完全是咎由自取  是我活该
I'm ready to pay for what I've done.
帮他把手铐解了
Get the cuffs off him, will you?
直升机马上就到
Chopper's on the way.
我会把你带回调查局
I'll be taking you back to FBI, all right?
这种病会一直伴有失忆的症状  鲍尔先生
Memory loss is consistent with the disease,Mr. Bauer.
但我没料到症状会出现地这么快
I just wouldn't have expected it to manifest this quickly.
不止是失忆
It's not just memory loss.
感觉好像
It feels like...
我不知该怎么说
I don't know exactly how to explain it.
我觉得
I feel like, uh,
就像我的部分机体丧失了能力
Like I'm losing some part of myself.
病的症状包括
The disease profile includes
人格转变  有时还会产生幻觉
Personality changes, someTimes even hallucinations.
但这是一种武器化了的病原体
But this is a weaponized pathogen
我们对其了解微乎其微
We don't know much about.
军方现在还在桑加拉的生化武器
Military's still combing through the remains
实验室的废墟中展开彻底搜查
Of the bioweapons lab in Sangala,
很快我们就能更进一步地了解了
So we expect to learn something very soon.
你刚才给了我控制身体发抖的药
You were able to give me something that controlled the shaking.
能再给我一些防止失忆的药吗
Is there anything that you can give me that would help me with this?
没有
No.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
知道了
Okay.
谢谢  失陪
Thank you. Excuse me.
杰克  还好吗
Jack, is it all right?
还好
Yeah, um,
我要对今天发生的事情做下笔录
I'm gonna need to go on record about everything that happened today.
必须要尽快
And we need to do it soon.
我不知道自己还能
I'm not sure how much longer I'm gonna be
保持清醒多久
Able to provide you with the details.
好吧
Okay.
我有点事要先对你讲
First, there's something that you need to know.
什么
What?
是金
It's about Kim.
她来了  杰克
She's here, Jack.
我告诉她你病了
I told her that you were sick
而且她可能有助于你的治疗
And that she might be able to help with the treatment.
你
You did...
你干嘛了
You didwhat?
过来
Come here.
你以为你是谁啊
Who the hell do you think you are?
你少自以为是
你觉得我好过吗
You think this is easy?
你以为你这样做很体贴吗
You think you understand what I'm going through?
你想错了
Because you don't.
我快不行了
I am dying.
但我没事的
And I was okay with it.
我还能独自承受这一切
I could handle it.
而现在你却让我面临如此境地
And now you've put in front of me the one thing,
你把她牵扯进来  这让我忍无可忍
The one thing that is gonna make this unbearable.
-杰克  听我说  -不  你听我说
- Jack, listen... - No, you listen to me.
我特地警告过你不要把我女儿牵扯进来
I specifically told you do not drag my daughter into this.
没人逼她做任何事情
No one dragged her into anything.
她一整天都想见你
She's been trying to see you all day.
什么
What?
她今早出席了参议院听证会
She was at the senate hearing this morning.
她特地从洛杉矶赶到这里
She flew out from L.A. to be there,
但我们在她见到你之前把你带了出来
But we pulled you out before she could see you.
她一整天都在不断给我们办公室留言
She's been leaving messages at our office all day.
只是他们现在才告诉我
They just didn't get to me till now.
如果你愿意  我可以告诉她你不在这
If you want, I can tell her that you're not here.
我可以告诉她你无法见她
I can tell her that you can't see her.
我不能这么做
Can't do that.
她在哪里
Where is she?
楼下大厅
Down the hall.
带我去
Show me.
爸
Daddy.
你感觉怎样
How are you feeling?
我  我没事
I'm-I'm okay.
不疼吗
You're not in any pain?
不疼
No.
过来坐吧
Come sit down.
沃克探员告诉过你我一直在找你吗
Didagent Walker tell you that I was trying to find you?
她说了
Yeah.
我想方设法打听你的下落
I've tried everything to track you down.
我找了国务院  私人侦探
State Department, private investigators.
每次得到了电话号码或者地址
Every Time I got a phone number or an address,
我赶到那里总是迟你一步
You were already gone.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我以为我远走高飞是为你好
I thought I was doing the best thing for you by staying away.
爸  我想死你了
Daddy, I've missed you so much.
我也一直在想你
I've missed you,too.
你要知道  因为我的缘故
You need to know how sorry I am
让你受了这么多苦  我有多么抱歉
For everything that you've had to live through because of me.
不  别这么说
No, don't do that.
别太自责了
Don't put that on yourself.
我才应该道歉
I'm the one that should apologize.
是我拒你于千里之外
I pushed you away.
我不仅没有为我一生所犯的过错
And instead of taking responsibility
而负起责任  反而责怪你
For all the mistakes I've made in my life, I blamed you.
我愚蠢至极
And it was stupid
也太不成熟了
And immature.
如今  我们错过的这些时光
And now, all the Time that we've lost...
沃克探员告诉我还有希望
Agent Walker told me that there's a chance--
一线希望  我可能救得了你
A small chance that I could help you,
而你却不希望我救你
And you don't want me to.
这个治疗还在临床试验阶段
The treatment is experimental.
我觉得不可行
And I don't think it's going to work.
你不想这么做  因为你害怕来求我
And you don't want to because you're afraidto ask me.
不
No.
这对你有风险
There's a risk to you.
风险很小
A small risk...
值得一试
Worth taking.
我觉得不值得
Not to me.
金  我快死了
Kim... I'm dying.
即便有能让我幸存的一线生机
And whatever small chance there is to stop that from happening
我也决不愿承受  让你坐在我身边
It is not worth the pain for me to let you
看着我死去时的那种切肤之痛
Sit there and watch me die.
爸  我不想失去你
Daddy, I don't want to lose you.
过来
Come here.
我不想失去你
I don't.
宝贝  一切都会好起来的
Sweetheart, it's going to be all right.
会好起来的  我保证
It's gonna be all right. I promise you.
怎么了
What is it?
What?
宝贝  抱歉
Sweetheart, I'm sorry...
但你还是走吧
But you need to go.
求你了  宝贝  求你了  爸爸求你了
Please, baby, please, I'm begging you.
我真的很爱你
I love you so much.
亲爱的  我也爱你  求你了  宝贝
Honey, I love you, too. please, baby.
谢谢  走吧
Thank you. Go.
2区岗哨呼叫调度中心  6号侧门安全
Perimeter 2 to Dispatch. Auxiliary gate 6 is clear.
收到  2区岗哨  坚守岗位
Copy that, P-2. hold your position.
别动
Freeze!
把手举起来
Show me your hands.
举起来
Get 'em up!
2区岗哨呼叫调度中心
P-2 to Dispatch.
一名探员被射杀  我扣留了一名嫌犯
I have an agent down and a suspect in custody.
红色警戒
Code red.
收到  2区岗哨
Copy that, P-2.
所有空余探员速速增援6号侧门
All available agents respond to auxiliary gate 6.
-把包放下  -红色警戒
- Drop the bag. - Code red.
把手放在引擎盖上
Hands on the hood.
[危险  危险军备物资]
Danger.Hazardous Materiel.
2区岗哨呼叫调度中心
P-2 to Dispatch.
帮我接莫斯探员  十万火急
Put me through to agent Moss. it's urgent.
我是莫斯探员
Agent Moss.
莫斯探员  我是戴维斯  在6号侧门
Agent Moss, this is Davis at auxiliary gate 6.
我抓到了一个斯塔克伍德的雇佣兵
I have a Starkwood op in custody.
他杀了一名探员
He killed one of our agents.
他随身携带一罐生化武器
He was carrying a canister of the bioweapon,
他正试图用我们的车辆偷运出去
Trying to smuggle it out using one of our vehicles.
什么  确定是生化武器吗
What?! are you sure?
就在我眼前
I'm looking at it right now.
戴维斯探员
Agent Davis?
戴维斯
Davis?!
我是沃克
Walker.
蕾妮  有人从封锁区6号门逃走
Renee, we got a breach in the cordon at gate 6.
是斯塔克伍德的一名雇佣兵
One of the Starkwood ops
他带走了一罐生化武器
He's got a canister of the bioweapon.
什么
What?
戴维斯探员已经确认
It was IDed by agent Davis,
我相信他已经被射杀
Who I believe has just been shot.
嫌犯可能正驾驶调查局车辆潜逃
The suspect may be fleeing in an FBI vehicle,
所以我要你封锁所有出去的道路
So I need you to close down all access roads,
让周边小组和首府警察保持警戒
And alert perimeter units and Metro Police.
詹尼丝  给我接通首府警局
Janis, get me DCMetro.
我将进行空中追捕
I'm gonna pursue it from the air.
快走  起飞
Let's go! let us up!
蕾妮
Renee,
通告国土安全局  让他们知道详情
Alert Homeland, let them know what's going on.
拉里  这是另一场袭击吗
Are we thinking this is another attack, Larry?
不清楚  但其中一罐中的朊病毒变体
I don't know, but there's enough prion variant
足以毁灭一座小城市
In one of those canisters to take out a small city.
米勒探员  我们周围是否有
Agent Miller, are there any major roadways
那个雇佣兵可能会走的主干道
In our perimeter that Starkwood operatives could have used?
有  长官  我们离42号高速公路很近
Yes, sir. We're coming up on highway 42.
要我们的人赶往那边吗
Should I turn us that way?
好  收到沃克探员的指示前
Yeah, let's head that way
我们先朝那边走
until we hear something from agent Walker.
收到
Roger that.
好  长官  我们会向国土安全局
Yes, sir. we'll keep Homeland apprised
实时汇报最新信息
With real-Time updates.
你登陆全球定位系统了吗
Didyou access the GPS locator system?
登陆了  我正在异频雷达收发机上
Yeah, I'm scanning transponders
扫描搜寻被盗调查局车辆
for the stolen FBI vehicle.
需要多久
How long will that take?
卫星重定位车辆位置后即可完成
As long as it takes for the satellite to reposition.
你和拉里通话时提到有人遇袭  对吗
When you spoke to Larry, you mentioned an attack?
提到了斯塔克伍德的雇佣兵
The Starkwood operative,
我们在找一罐被盗的生化武器
We're trying to find a stolen canister of the bioweapon.
我还以为托尼·阿尔梅达销毁了所有武器
I thought Tony Almeida destroyed all the weapons.
显然没有
Apparently not.
这个家伙是怎么越过封锁线的呢
How didthis operative get past our perimeter?
他射杀了我们的两名探员
Shot and killed two of our agents.
找到了
This is it.
嫌犯正从烟树大道下了42号高速公路
The suspect is getting off highway 42 at Smoketree Avenue.
他正开往工业走廊
He's heading toward the industrial corridor.
帮我接通各部门公共频道
Put me on the interagency channel.
-请讲  -所有小组注意
- Go ahead. - All units,
我是调查局的沃克探员
This is agent Walker with FBI.
嫌犯已在烟树大道出了42号高速公路
Suspect has exited highway 42 at Smoketree.
正向北驱驶  开往工业走廊
He's heading north into the industrial corridor.
附近小组  请回答
Units in the vicinity, please respond.
蕾妮  是我
Renee, it's me.
我们正赶往烟树大道
We're over Smoketree right now.
我们正重定向  将紧跟目标
We're redirecting, and we'll tighten our pursuit.
收到  我会命特警A小队赶往现场
Got it. I'll reroute SWAT team Alpha to the scene.
特警A小队 我们要在费尔法科斯县边界处
SWAT team Alpha, we need to set up a roadblock
建立一道路障
At the Fairfax county line.
首府警察正封锁这条地区的边界线
DCMetro's covering the district line in case he tries
-以防他折回逃脱  -收到  前往县边界处
- To double back.- Copy that. County line.
长官
Sir.
看到了
I have a visual.
好  看到了
Yeah. got him.
下降些
Send us lower.
他拐下路了  放我们下去
Yeah, he's pulling off the road. Get us down there now.
蕾妮  我是拉里  嫌犯改为步行
Renee, it's Larry. suspect is on foot.
等不及后援了
We can't wait for backup.
我们现在行动
We're moving in right now.
好  特警队还需几分钟赶到
All right. SWAT team's a few minutes out.
-小心行事  拉里  -好
- Careful, Larry. - Yeah.
记住  嫌犯携带毒气罐
Remember, suspect has a canister,
不要轻易射击
So pic your shots.
可能的话  活捉他
If possible, let's take him alive.
遵命  长官
Yes, sir.
我们得下机
We got to get out of here.
阿尔梅达  掩护我  走
Almeida, cover. let's go.
快
Come on!
放松
Sir, relax.
-我没事  -放松
- I'm okay. - Relax.
-忍一下  -托尼
- Swallow. - Tony.
托尼
Tony!
怎么
What...?
抱歉  拉里
I'm sorry, Larry.
老天
Oh... god...
让我看看
Let me see it.
我们该怎么脱身呢
How the hell do we get out of here?
你带上它  找个地方藏身
I want you to take this, find a place to hide.
-等我电话  -你呢
- Wait for my call. - What about you?
我等调查局的人来
I'm gonna wait on the FBI,
想办法帮你脱身
Figure out a way to get you out of here.
快走
Go!